你好，我是菲比布菲 我底下有宝宝要出来
I'm Phoebe Buffay,and I have babies coming out.
好，你开始阵痛了吗？
Have you started having contractions?
还没，听说会很痛，真的吗？
Not yet. I heard they really hurt. Do they?
这个嘛… 天哪
-Well… -Oh,my God!
哪一位是父亲？
Which of you is the father?
他们都不是，我弟才是
None of them are. The father is my brother.
好
Okey
我一定会很怀念你那样吓别人
I'll miss watching you freak people out like that.
菲比，快，这是要给宝宝看的
This is for the babies to look at someday.
在生产前你有话要说吗？ 好
Do you want to say anything before it starts?-Oh,Okey
孩子们，我是菲比姑姑 真想赶快见到你们
Hi,kids! It's me,Aunt Phoebe.Can't wait to see you.
请不要弄痛我
Please don't hurt me!
你们怎么那么慢？ 两辆车是一起出发的
What took you so long?Your cab left when ours did.
我们回去拿我的外套
We went back because I forgot my jacket.
没错
That's right
你没穿外套啊
You're not wearing one.
真是的，我又忘了
Oh,man! I did it again!
得有人通知弗兰克和艾丽斯
Someone has to call Frank and Alice.
我妈也想…乔伊，你干什么？
My mom might… Joey，What are you doing?
我得拍生产前的镜头
I've got to get the "before" shot!
本集播出：“三胞胎”又名“总第一百集”
The One With The Triplets AKA The One Hundredth
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
菲比，我们问过护士了
We spoke to the nurse.
你的医生之所以迟到是因为 她不来了
The reason your doctor is late...is because she's not coming.
什么？ 她在浴室跌倒撞到头
She hit her head in the shower.
天哪，那个蠢女人
Oh,my God. She's so stupid!
菲比，不会有事的
Phoebe,it's gonna be okay.
你说得轻松 你的阴道又没有宝宝要出来
I don't see three kids coming out of your vagina!
听着，护士说这个医生很好 对，他是妇产科主任
Listen. The nurse said the doctor is wonderful.He's head of the department.
老天爷救救我 怎么了？
All right. Oh,dear God,save me!
第一次阵痛来了
I'm having my first contraction!
感觉不错 好
Oh,it's not bad.
生命的奇迹开始了…
And so the miracle of birth begins. And l
你没事吧？
You okay?
有个地方好痛
Something hurts.
是感同身受，好感人喔
It's sympathy pains. That's so sweet!
我不知道我有那么在意
I didn't know I cared that much.
你好
Hello！-Hi
菲比，我是哈洛医生
Phoebe，I'm Dr. Harad.
我负责替你接生
I'll be delivering your babies.
有我在你放心，我是老手了
You'll be in good hands. I've been doing this a long time.
我马上回来帮你做检查
I'll be back to do your internal.
你先放轻松，目前一切都很好
Just relax,everything looks great.
还有，我爱方奇（《欢乐时光》的主角）
And also,I love Fonzie.
他刚才说他爱方奇吗？ 听起来是
Did he just say he loves Fonzie?That's what it sounded like.
好
All right.
我来晚了吗？ 还没有人出来吧？
Am I late? Nobody came out yet,right?
没有，还没开始呢 艾丽斯呢？
No,we haven't started yet. Where's Alice?
在德拉威，不过她正在赶来 目前先由我充当教练
Delaware. Until she gets here,I'll be your coach.
放心，她有教我拉马兹（生产呼吸法）什么的
Don't worry. She told me about the LaMazda stuff.
就是在月底前生产 就能获得2%的补助
If you get the babies out by month's end...you get two percent financing.
对
Ya
莫妮卡，你一定会很以我为荣 我帮我们约到两个不可思议的可爱护士
Monica,you're gonna be very proud of me.I just got us dates with two unbelievably cute nurses.
上帝啊
Oh,my!
是男看护 在我想像中不是
They're male nurses.Not in my head.
总之他们约我们周六晚上出去 如何？
They want to take us out Saturday night! What do you say?
我看算了
I don't think so.
什么？你在说什么呢？
What are you talking about?
是你劝我忘记罗斯向前看的
You've been telling me to get over Ross and move on.
我向前看了，你得陪我 你说，你为什么不去
I'm moving on and so are you.Why don't you want to go?
不如你说一个理由 我再告诉你是对是错
Why don't you give me a good reason...and I'll tell you if it's true.
什么？ 没那么简单吧
-What? -Harder than it sounds,isn't it?
总之你也要去 我还答应他们下班一起吃果冻
You're coming. And when they get off...we'll go get some Jello with them.
没错，永远有一屋子的果冻
There's always room for Jello.
你为什么能说得那么色？
How do you make that dirty?
简单，我什么都能说得很色 你听
It's easy. I can do it with anything.
奶奶的鸡肉沙拉…
Grandma's chicken salad....
罗斯，拍这里
Get a shot of this.
宝宝们 这是你们出生当天的头条
These are the headlines when you were born.
女宝宝把头转开，男宝宝…
Now,girl baby,turn away. And boy babies...
看，这就是你出生当月的裸女（花花公子封面）
...check it out!This is what naked women looked like when you were born.
尽情欣赏吧
Now let's dive into the good stuff.
好，阵痛又来了
Okay,I'm having another one!
这次也不太痛…错，很痛
This one doesn't hurt eith Yes,it does!
我有点希望已经生了
I was kind of hoping that was it.
莫妮卡和瑞秋呢？
Where are Monica and Rachel,anyway?
可能跟约她们的护士在一起
A couple of nurses asked them out.
是吗？男看护？ 对，我也很失望
Really? Male nurses?Yeah,I was bummed too.
她们要去约会？什么时候？
So they're going on dates.When?
星期六吧…
-I think Saturday.
他怎么了？ 他感同身受
-What's with him? -Sympathy pains.
我本来很感动 现在我觉得他只是想抢锋头
It was sweet at first,but now I think he's trying to steal my thunder.
好，来看看你的情况
Let's see what we got here.
你知道吗？ 方奇跟三胞胎约过会
Oh,you know,Fonzie dated triplets.
你一直提到的这位方奇 他是另一位医生吗？
This Fonzie person you keep referring to...is that another doctor?
不是 方奇是亚瑟方塞瑞利的匿称
Oh,no,no.Fonzie is the nickname of Arthur Fonzerelli.
也叫方子
The Fonz.
好
All right.
其实不会很怪吧？
It's not that weird,is it?
怪得不得了
It's very weird!
我才不要听某人告诉我 我子宫扩张了“一滴滴”（方奇的口头禅）
I don't want some guy down there telling me I'm "dilated-a-mundo."
老实说，他不是在模仿方奇…
He doesn't seem to be impersonating Fonzie
你在干什么？干嘛替他辩解？
What are you doing?Why are you defending him?
去帮我另外找一个没有发疯 不是方奇的医生
Just get me another doctor who isn't crazy and doesn't Fonzie!
其实他不是…
Again,it's not
你在这里
Hey,there you are!
有件事应该让你知道
There's something you should know.
是你要跟护士约会的事吗？
Is this about you dating the nurse?
我听乔伊说了 我一点也不在意
Joey told me.I am so fine.
你和我又没什么 我们只是玩玩
You and l,we're just nothing.Just goofing around.
其实我是想告诉你我打算推掉
I was about to tell you I was getting out of it.
既然我们只是玩玩 那我就跟他出去好了
But if we're just "goofing around," maybe I will go out with him.
好，那我也要
Fine. Maybe I will too.
喂，你们看我去礼品部发现了什么
Hey! Look what I found in the gift shop.
起来，快起来
Get up! Get up! Get up!
菲比，这是欧伯曼医生
Phoebe，This is Dr. Oberman.
他对方奇或者“欢乐时光”的所有人物都没什么感觉
He has no strong feelings about Fonzie...or any of the Happy Days gang.
你要升几年级了？
You're going into what grade?
我刚升住院医师 常有人那样问我，我提前…
I'm actually a first-year resident. I graduated early.
我也是
Me too.
罗斯，或许我应该强调 我是要已成年的医师
I should have specified I'd need a grown-up doctor.
我绝对有能力…别说了杜吉（《天才小医生》的角色）！
Really,I'm fully qualified…-Doogie!
到底有没有人了解我快生了？
Doesn't anybody understand that I'm going to be having babies soon?
你走，走啊小毛头
Go,little boy! Go!
你把他弄哭了
Oh,cool. You made him cry!
崔比亚尼先生，你有肾结石
Mr. Tribbiani,I'm afraid you've got kidney stones.
有别的可能吗？ 就是肾结石
Well,what else could it be?It's kidney stones.
或是…？ 肾结石
Or....Kidney stones.
如果是别的毛病… 绝对是肾结石
-lf it was something else? -Well,that would be "kidney stones."
差不多了
You're getting there.
这些宝宝很幸运 是吗，为什么？
These babies are very,very lucky.They are? Why?
他们的生日日期是方子的一半
They'll be born on the Fonz's half-birthday.
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
我澄清一下，我不是方奇
Just to clarify...I'm not Fonzie.
说真的 你能替你弟生孩子真的很棒
It's a terrific thing that you're having these babies for Frank and Alice.
的确
No,it is.
我可以告诉你一个秘密吗？ 你说
Can I tell you a secret?
我要自己留一个
I want to keep one.
天哪，我会上新闻
Oh,I'm gonna be on the news.
菲比，别开玩笑了 你明知你不能这么做
You must be kidding.You know you can't keep one of these babies.
为什么？搞不好可以 你怎么知道
Maybe I can. You don't know.
我当然知道 弗兰克他们一定三个都要
I do. Frank and Alice will want to keep all their children.
不一定
Maybe not. You know?
三个宝宝很多 也许他们正在找机会送走一个
Three babies are a handful.Maybe they'll want to unload one.
我不想因为没开口而失去机会
I hate to miss an opportunity because I didn't ask.
菲比，这件事太不理智了
Phoebe,no. This is insane.
你就问问看嘛 我？
Just ask him.What? Me?
我不能自己问 你知道那样多不成体统吗？
I can't ask him!Do you know how inappropriate that would be?
总之你去找弗兰克谈 探探他的口风
All I'm saying is,just talk to Frank.Just feel him out.
不行，我怎么能叫弗兰克 送你一个孩子
No. I will not ask Frank to give you one of his kids.
你说得对
You're right.
就说是你要的
Tell him it's for you.
好一点了吗？ 一点点吧
Feeling better,sweetie?Maybe a little.
真希望你没看到我吐
Wish you hadn't seen me throw up.
我也希望
Me too.
我刚刚听说，怎么回事？ 肾结石
I just heard. What's up?Kidney stones!
通常我们会用冲击波震碎结石 但你的结石已经太靠近膀胱
Ordinarily,we try to break the stones up with shock waves.But they're too close to the bladder.
不是等你排尿排出来 就是从尿道往上…
Either we wait for you to pass them or else go up the urethra
不行，不能往上 绝对不考虑往上
No,no,no,no. Nothing is going up,okay?Up is not an option.
尿道是什么？
What's a urethra?
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
你问他了吗？
Did you ask him?
我还没有机会跟他独处
No,I haven't had a chance yet.
我的时间有限
I'm kind of on a clock here.
方奇
Oh,Fonzie.
我一直都很喜欢魔克（也是《欢乐时光》中的角色）
You know who I always liked? Mork.
收回收回收回
Undo it. Undo it.
方奇遇见魔克 魔克把方奇结冻
Fonzie met Mork.Mork froze Fonzie.
对，但…
Yes，but
但是方奇本来就很酷
But Fonzie was already cool.
所以他不会有事，对吧？
So he wasn't hurt. Right?
也对
Yeah,that's right.
你好吗？ 很好，医生说随时都会生
How you doing?Okay. Doctor says any minute now.
艾丽斯马上就会到 你能不能帮个忙…
You know,Alice is going to be here so soon.You couldn't just do me a favor
先憋住？
and,like,hold them in?
抱歉，我正在处理你请我帮的上一个忙
Sorry,I'm in the middle of the last favor you asked me to do.
瑞秋
Rachel
莫妮卡，他是丹 我们星期六的男伴之一
This is Dan,one of the guys we're dating on Saturday.
丹，这是莫妮卡
Dan，Monica
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
你好丹，我很期待星期六的约会 非常期待
Hello Dan，I'm really looking forward to Saturday night. Really!
丹，你是护士不是医生？
So,Dan...nurse,not a doctor,huh?
有点娘娘腔对吧？
Kind of girlie,isn't it?
钱德
Chandler
没关系 这只是医学院的实习学分
That's okay. I'm doing this to get through medical school.
而且海湾战争时 感觉没那么娘娘腔
And it didn't feel "girlie" during the Gulf War.
那当然
Sure.
感谢你保家卫国
Thanks for doing that for us,by the way.
何必等到星期六 你明天有空吗？
Why wait till Saturday? Are you free tomorrow?
行啊，我找人代班 太好了
Sure. I'll get somebody to cover me.Great!
我们星期六去约个会如何？
Hey,you and me,Saturday night?
不要 很好
-No. -All right,very good!
这一回很痛
This is a big one.
把它弄出来
Get these things out of me!
深呼吸，深呼吸可以止痛
Breathe! Breathe through the pain.
我想吃止痛药！我想吃止痛药
I want the drugs,Ross!
我也是！我也是
I do too! I do too!
我爱你，再见
Yeah,I love you. Okay,bye.
艾丽斯的妈妈说她出发5小时了 她早就该到了
That was Alice's mom. Alice left five hours ago.She should be here.
放心，她会赶上的 好
She'll make it on time.
弗兰克，三个宝宝耶 还真多，对吧？
So,Frank...three babies. That just seems like a lot,huh?
我不觉得
Not to me.
很好
Fair enough.
扩张10公分，该生了
You're at ten centimeters. Time to start having babies.
请父亲留下来就好
I want only the father here.
菲比再见 加油
-We love you. -Good luck.
我们爱你
Love you
丹，再见 再见，莫妮卡
Bye Dan. -Bye Monica
再见， #@
Bye…
我要产钳，消毒毛巾 和31频道
I need a clamp,a sterile towel and Channel 31.
那是什么？
What is that?
天哪 不会，这一集很棒（《欢乐时光》）
Oh,my God!Oh,no,no! It's a good one.
方奇会打手鼓
Fonzie plays the bongos.
准备好了吗？该用力了
Ready? Time to try pushing.
准备好了吗？该撒尿了
Ready? Time to try peeing.
等等！是“差不多”该撒尿了
Wait,wait,wait,wait! It's almost time to try peeing.
用力，很好，专心用力 有了，我看到头了
Push. Concentrate on pushing.I see the head.
万岁！他有头
Yes,it has a head!
继续用力，加油
Keep pushing. Come on.
居然有人从你肚子里跑出来
I can't believe somebody's coming out!
有人从你肚子里跑出来 是我儿子
There's somebody coming out of you!-It's my son!
这是你的第一个宝宝
All right.Here's your first baby!
万岁！小男生出来了
Yes! We got a baby boy!
小小弗兰克
Frank Junior,Junior!
他长得怎样？ 恶心死了
How does he look?So gross!
可以再用力了吗？ 我已经生一个了，不要烦我
Okay. You ready to push again?I already had a baby. Leave me alone!
加油，你一定行
Come on,you can do it! You can do it!
万岁！小莱丝莉出来了
Little Leslie's here! We got another one!
天哪，我居然有两个孩子了
Oh,my God! I can't believe I have two children.
真吓人
How scary is that?
小钱德，该出来了 快啊，小钱德
Come on,little Chandler,it's time to be born.
他出来了，他出来了
He's coming! Yes,he's coming!
他的小东西呢？
Hey,where's his thing?
钱德是女生
Chandler's a girl!
天哪，幼稚园回忆重现
Oh,God! Kindergarten flashback.
一定是照超音波看错了 医生以为是个男生
They read the sonogram wrong,because they thought it was a boy.
但钱德是女生！钱德是女生
But Chandler's a girl!
很好，继续叫
Okay,keep saying it.
我来晚了吗？
-Am I too late?
不会，一切都很好 有30个指头和30个脚趾
-No,no. Everything's okay.There's 30 fingers and 30 toes.
我们的孩子生了？ 对
We have our babies?
我们有孩子了
We have our babies.
天哪 你办到了
Oh,my God!You did it,man.
你要看看它们吗？
Would you like to see them?
好小喔
They're so small.
我明天跟你联络 好
-I'll call you tomorrow. -Great.
你真的要跟那个护士男约会？
Are you really going to date that nurse man?
你和我只是玩玩 我当然也可以跟他玩玩
You and I are just "goofing around."I thought,why not "goof around" with him?
我不知道你有没有查过字典
I don't know if you've looked up "goofing around" in the dictionary.
我有，“玩玩”的定义是
Well,I have...and the technical definition is:
两个好朋友，非常在乎对方
Two friends who care a lot about each other...
在床上很“性”福
...and have amazing sex...
而且想多跟对方相处
...and just want to spend more time together.
如果你用的是让你生气的版本 那我们应该买我的版本给你
But if you have this new dictionary that gets you mad at me then we have to get you my original one.
我实在很不会说
I am so bad at this.
比你想像的要好 真的？
-You're better than you think you are. -Really?
好，那…
Okay. So if?
要见好就收 我也觉得够了
-Know when to stop. -I sensed that I should stop.
我们没事了？ 没事了
So we're okay? -Ya
我去告诉丹我不跟他约会了
I'm gonna go tell Dan that it's not gonna happen.
不要跳舞 好
-Don't do the dance. -Right.
我觉得我最喜欢你
You're my favorite.
你抱的是哪一个？ 无所谓
-Which one do you have? -I don't care.
弗兰克和艾丽斯说 他们还要打电话
Frank and Alice want me to tell you they're making phone calls.
你有没有问他们… 这个嘛…
Did you talk to them about,you know....
没有，亲爱的
No,honey.
好
Okey
反正也不太可能
It was a long shot.
让我跟宝宝独处一下好吗？ 好
You guys? Can I just have a second alone with the babies? -Oh，ya
你们都在了
So here you are.
我对着培养皿跟你们说话 仿佛是昨天的事
Seems like yesterday I was talking to you in that petri dish.
大家都说生产最难熬 其实跟你们分开才是
Everyone said labor was the hardest thing.But they were wrong. This is.
这段日子真的很开心
Well,I had the most fun with you guys.
真想带你们回家每天看着你们
I wish I could take you home and see you every day.
我就当你们最喜欢的姑姑吧
I'll settle for being your favorite aunt.
艾丽斯的妹妹家有游泳池 但你们在我肚子里游过
I know Alice's sister has a pool,but you lived in me.
那就这样了
Okay,so we're cool.
我们会处得很好
We're gonna be great.
击掌
Little high-fives.
你都哭了
Well,if you're going to cry....
菲比，我们以你为荣 你真了不起
Phoebe,we are so proud of you. You're amazing!
我知道
I know.
真的有那么痛吗？ 有，你绝对受不了
Does it hurt as bad as they say?You won't be able to take it.
既然小钱德是个女生 他们打算叫她什么？
Now that little Chandler is a girl,what'll they name her?
就叫她钱德
They'll call her Chandler.
这个名字有点男性化吧？
Kind of a masculine name,don't you think?
你都能用了
It works on you.
也许可以把它女性化 例如钱蒂叶特
Maybe they can girlie it up a bit,like Chandlerette.
艾丽斯叫她钱妮潘妮
Alice called her Channy-fanny.
钱妮潘妮
Ha-ha,Channy-fanny.